tapology.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy | Tapology

#### Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and share information we obtain through your use of www.tapology.com and any affiliated web sites, subdomains, web or mobile applications, and online services owned or operated by Tapology (collectively the "Site"). We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. By using the Site, you consent to our Privacy Policy.

#### Information We Collect

We collect several categories of information as a result of your use of the Site, depending on how you choose to use the Site.

Automatically Collected Information: We automatically collect certain information, including information pertaining to your IP address, browser type, browser language, operating system, computer type (including mobile device type), access time and duration, landing page, and the pages you accessed during your visit, as well as any web pages and URLs you utilized to arrive on or depart from the Site. We collect and store this information when you use the Site, even if you have not created an account on the Site.

Account and Profile Information: When you register as a Member of the Site you provide us with additional information, including a Site username and password and your e-mail address. As a Member of the Site, you may elect to use various Site features which provide us with additional information about you, such as a personal User statement and description, a personal photo or graphic, personal fight predictions and commentary, custom rankings and commentary, forum posts, and forum post ratings and replies.

Communications: If you correspond with us by e-mail or through our Site content submission forms, we may retain those e-mail messages or Site submissions. We do not publish personal user data that you supply to us via these communications.

Your Content: We collect and store the information and content that you post on the Site, including your posts, comments, fight picks, rankings, wiki entries and edits, and related information. We may also collect and store metadata further identifying information about the content you post, including the date and time as well as aggregate information about your content.

Cookies: We also use cookies, which are small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters identifying your browser which are stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie does not collect personal information about you. We use cookies to speed your Site login, validate your authorization, customize Site options and features based on your preferences, and otherwise facilitate your use of the Site and improve Site quality. In addition, third parties who place advertisements on the Site may also utilize cookies to ensure their systems work properly and to collect information. Cookies set by third parties are governed by the privacy policies of those third parties and not by this Privacy Policy. Generally, you can set your browser not to accept cookies or to notify you if you are sent a cookie, giving you the opportunity to choose whether or not to accept the cookie. Please note that if you set your browser not to accept cookies, certain areas of the Site may not function properly.

#### How We Use Information We Collect

We do not sell your personal data, such as your name and contact information, to third parties to use for their own marketing purposes. We reserve the right to monitor the content you post on the Site. We have the right to modify or remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason. For more information, view our Terms of Use. We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

Provide our services: To provide you the services we offer on the Site and to communicate with you. By providing us with your e-mail address, you consent to our using it to send you site-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your e-mail address to send you other messages, such as news, updates, changes to the Site, or special offers. If you do not want to receive some or all of these e-mail messages (other than notices required by law), you may edit the settings on your preferences page. Please understand that these changes may not take effect immediately.

Personalization: We use your information to tailor the content and information that we may display to you on the Site or send to you, and to personalize your experience on the Site.

Advertising: To display interest-based advertising to you on the Site, to improve our advertising and measurement systems so we can show you relevant ads, and to measure the effectiveness and reach of ads and services.

Marketing and Promotions: For marketing and promotional purposes, such as to send you news and newsletters, special offers and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about products, events and information we think may interest you, including information about third party products and services.

Analytics: To gather metrics to better understand how users interact with the Site; to evaluate and improve the Site; and to develop new products and services.

Comply with law: To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.

Prevent Misuse: Where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal or improper activities, threats to safety, or violations of our Terms of Use or this Privacy Policy.

#### How We Share Information

Tapology does not lend or sell your personal information. We may provide information about you or your content to third parties without personally identifying you. We may do this for purposes such as managing data, analyzing how the Site is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, or personalizing advertisements and promotions. If we do this, such use of your information will be bound by this Privacy Policy.

We will not disclose personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to (a) conform to the law, comply with legal process served on us, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities; (b) to enforce our Terms of Use, take precautions against liability, to investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations, to assist government enforcement agencies, or to protect the security or integrity of our site; (c) to exercise or protect the rights, property, or safety of Tapology, its users or others; or (d) in the event we are acquired by or merge with another entity.

Some information and content that you post on the Site becomes available to the public. If you remove some of this content, such as your personal User profile information, copies may temporarily remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored the information. Other components of your Site usage, including predictions, rankings and post ratings you have supplied to the Site, may not be available for removal even if you choose to terminate your usage of the Site.

We may share non-personal information, such as aggregate Site data, anonymous usage data, trends and the like with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for Site activities.

We may allow certain third parties such as ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Site. These third parties use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content We do not provide any personally identifiable information to these third parties without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks us to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third parties. We do not control the activities of such advertisers.

#### How We Store and Protect Information

The data you provide to us or that is collected or created about you is stored on secure (non-public) servers. We engage certain third party service providers for this purpose. This data resides at various physical locations worldwide, including at locations outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). The EEA consists of all European Union member states plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein. The data may also be processed or modified at various waypoints prior to reaching its storage location. You hereby agree to this transfer, storage and processing protocol.

We use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. We also ordinarily seek to require encrypted communication layers such as ssl/https in order for you to access and use the Site. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of all information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems and those of the third party providers we engage. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any physical, technical, or managerial safeguards of this Site or any third party provider.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you access to your account. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your e-mail communications with us, at all times. We may store information we collect in locations outside of our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

#### Compromise of Personal Information

In the event we should determine that your personal information has been compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will attempt to promptly notify you in accordance with this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

#### Your Rights and Choices About Your Information

You may decline to submit personally identifiable information to us, in which case we may not be able to provide certain services to you.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to request that we cease such processing at any time by contacting us.

The law gives you the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you. You may do so by first contacting us. We first require that you prove your identity with two (2) pieces of valid identification. Upon receipt and confirmation we will then provide you with a copy of your personal user data.

In addition, you may request that your personal user information be erased from our records. We will comply with your requests in accordance with applicable law. Please note that some categories of information, including publicly available records and information, non-private site submissions and aggregate information, are not subject to removal. To make such a request please contact us.

#### Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register on the Site. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us.

#### Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices, information or content of sites linked to or from our Site. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including those that have a link on our Site, is subject to that site's own rules and policies.

#### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

© 2018 Tapology. All rights reserved.
